Meet Novation Launch Control. [music]
A compact new addition to the Launch
Control range.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello Walker. Hello Matt. Welcome back.
Thank you.
>> Super booth 2026 this is my first video
of day two.
So I had to get here because
I I read a little bit about this and I
saw your video. This is the new
Plexophone, right? That's right. So what
is it?
>> It's the Sound Hack Plexophone. It is a
new stereo spatial texturizer module
that we developed in conjunction with
Tom Erb. We've of course worked with him
on many projects before from the
Morphagene to Spectrophone, Mimeophone
and plenty of others.
So this module is encoded from scratch
on a brand new idea by Tom on our latest
digital hardware and it is taking the
idea of Plexis which gives it its name.
Uh and that is the Latin root for weave
and what it's doing is weaving some
sound together through a number of
different feedback paths and uh what you
might say delay taps and the Plexis
control being the key control it will
determine the overall number of
uh of feedback paths and delay taps and
how complex the relationship between
those is. So when we have Plexis turned
all the way down as it is now, the
module operates
as if it's kind of like a reverb because
many of the paths are uh they're all
very tightly interwoven to create this
sense of uh echoing space
and the size control here will operate
like the size control of a reverb. Now
as we turn the Plexis up more and more,
we'll start to hear
the individual taps uh beginning to
stick out in the mix a little more.
>> Yeah. The overall relationship between
them becomes less
complex. There become fewer and fewer of
them and it becomes more like a
multi-tap Oh, yeah.
>> echo, and the size is now
akin to a rate control on an echo
module.
And we can
always
move very smoothly from one extreme to
the other of Plexis.
And a lot of the
development time on this module was just
ensuring that
we can do all this very smoothly. Very
smooth switch from
reverb to delay.
Very smooth modulation of size.
Cool.
Wow.
Smooth modulation of timbre parameters
like color.
>> You just sending that an envelope there
from Maths? That's right. Just a very
simple cycling function there that will
determine
the timbre at any given moment.
>> That's great.
>> The diffuse and color are our timbre
parameters, and then we also have
uh the couple and skew, which are stereo
operations. And we'll go into those in
more detail when we get closer to
release, but essentially they're
determining couple uh determining how
the left and right channels are
interacting sound-wise, and skew giving
some other options for interacting with
the left and right channels
control-wise.
Cool.
So, I'm trying to get an idea of the
kind of the signal path in a way, you
know, um You want to hear the dry
signal? It kind of Well, I'm just
wondering kind of it
you know, it sounds to me like
everything's kind of working together.
It's not It's not necessarily a linear
signal path throughout the module. Yes.
>> It seems like you've got feedback
and elements working on each other in
different ways, and That's for sure. So,
these parameters are highly interrelated
to each other because
we're always working on a different
number of delay paths with Plex is
changing the number of delay paths. It's
also changing the relation between them.
And the controls are all operating on at
any given time a number of different
paths in different ways. So, the
controls are really highly interrelated
and
developing this module was a lot about
finding the exact relations between them
so that they could all interact without
anything causing the whole system to
explode, which was happening a lot
during development, but we I feel like
we've fine-tuned it very nicely and it's
very playable. It's modeless. You can
reach every single extreme of parameter
from any place at any time.
We also have the uh
the send gate input.
Okay.
>> This is a one little one last little
trick I'd want to show you, which if we
if we hold that low, I'm patching a
dummy cable here to it here. It just
doesn't send anything through to the
Plex, right?
Um but if I send a gate in,
um then whatever's coming through at
that moment that the gate is high will
be sent in and then continue to echo out
through the through the paths.
And then when the gate goes low again,
um you can kind of depending on the
decay or whatever, you can still hear it
echoing out, but new things are not
brought in. So, this can be really
useful if you want to send like a gate
sequence, say from the even output of my
GTE here, we could send just individual
notes of a sequence through
>> [laughter]
>> so that not it's not just echoing
everything, but you're getting some kind
of like pointless echoes that are
helping helping it work with the shape
and contour of your sequence and add
some depth to specific places. So.
>> It's great. I mean, the final output of
it isn't a typical delay or reverb
sound, if you ask me. It it feels like
it's a very kind of blurred world that
they're both situating themselves into.
I'm it's quite a hard one to describe,
really. But, it sounds absolutely
lovely. It's Yeah, as I like to call
things, they're really vibey. Vibey.
Very much so.
And it can give you really nice
kind of beautiful textures to overlay or
have things sit into, or you can get
wild with modulation and turn it into
kind of its own entire voice instrument
in itself in a lot of ways, so. Can you
show us like a really big decay sort of
big
sort of
how extreme can this go if we wanted to
go wild with it?
Oh, nice.
Listen to that.
Wow.
Awesome.
Brilliant. So, when can we expect to see
this available? We'll be shipping this
in early June at a
MSRP of 469 USD. 469 USD. Amazing.
Great stuff. Um
as as always, make noise, you know, keep
making noise and making these wonderful
products for us. Thank you.
>> Thanks so much for coming by, Matt.
>> Cheers, man.
>> [music]